Nazmus Sakib

Montreal, Quebec, Canada. H3W 1W2 🏫

+1 (514) 621-4478

sakibn55@gmail.com

https:/www.linkedin.com/in/nazmus-insakib-531997a9

https://github.com/sakibn55 🌐

https://nazmus.netlify.app 🌐

https://www.fiverr.com/nazmussakib680

I am a full stack developer with over 4 years of experience. I have developed and maintained complex Web and RESTful applications using PHP, Laravel, MySQL and JavaScript along with various other technologies. I always love working with technically strong team where I can solve complex problems with a good balance of freedom and responsibility.

Key Skills

- HTML
- JavaScript
- VueJs
- PHP
- C#
- CakePHP
- Agile
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Communication Skills
- Technical Skills
- Critical Thinking Skills
- Concept of Test Driven Design (TDD)

- CSS
- jQuery
- MySQL
- Laravel
- Drupal
- Git
- Time Management Skills
- Problem Solving Skills
- Project Management Skills
- Analytical Thinking Skills
- English Proficiency
- Postman

Education

2019 - 2021

Attestation of College Studies (A.C.S) Diploma CDI College, Montreal, Canada

Programmer Analyst/Internet Solution Developer

Bachelor of Science

Leading University, Sylhet, Bangladesh

- Computer Science and Engineering
- Graduated with 3.09 CGPA
- Joint secretary of Leading University Computer Club

2012

Higher Secondary School Certificate

Brindaban Govt. College, Habiganj, Sylhet, Bangladesh

- Science
- Graduated with 4.40 GPA

2010

Secondary School Certificate

Govt. High School, Habiganj, Sylhet, Bangladesh

- Science
- Graduated with 5.00 GPA

Work Experience

MAY 2022 - PRESENT

Web Developer/ Laps, Montreal, QC

- Modularization.
- Pricing
- Ace Admin

Laravel Developer/ Giving Gateway, Toronto, ON (Remote)

- Working on a Donation App where Donors can donate on Campaigns on a Installment, Monthly and One time Donation Basis.
- Design, code and debug applications in Laravel
- · Software analysis, code analysis, requirements analysis, software review
- Identification of code metrics, system risk analysis
- Build RESTful API

JANUARY 2021 - MAY 2021

Laravel Developer / LSA Education Canada

• Developed Client WEB applications by applying experience in Laravel MVC Framework. [https://www.lsaeducation.com]

SEPTEMBER 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2019

Jr. Software Engineer / SJ INNOVATION LLC

- Developed WEB applications by applying experience in Drupal, PHP, Laravel, CakePHP, and JavaScript.
- Took the lead of a team of 7 to maintain and deliver 350+ projects for Janssen & Janssen and Janssen Medical Cloud UK and Ireland. [https://www.janssenmedicalcloud.co.uk/, https://www.janssenmedicalcloud.ie/]
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for creating well-organized project plans
- Analyzed code defects and failures and presented code refactors and design fixes
- Tuned and improved software source code based upon new user requirements and technical guidelines
- Followed Agile Method
- Contributed to daily scrum meetings with team updates

APRIL 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2018

Software Engineer Internship / SJ INNOVATION LLC

- Debugging and testing code
- Documenting and testing new software applications
- Researching, investigating and fixing a wide range of technical issues
- Collaborating with senior leaders
- Approaching problems and creating solutions
- Proactively learning about new technologies

Other Work Experience

2020 - PRESENT

Self-Employment/Fiverr.com/nazmussakib680

- Working as Part-Time
- Completed 20+ Project

Training

- LICT Top-Up IT Training
 - o Duration: 300rs Year 2017
 - o Batch code: LICT_TUP_LUSYL_01_WebDev
 - o portal.bdskills.com/certificates
 - o Graduate ID: G026124
- Drupal Training
 - SJ Innovation LLC

Honors & Awards

- Performer of the month
 - o Honor date: July 2019
 - o Honor issuer: SJ INNOVATION LLC

• Performer of the month

o Honor date: February 2019

o Honor issuer: SJ INNOVATION LLC

Volunteer Experience

- Joint Secretary
 - o Leading University Computer Club
 - o Jan 2017 Jan 2018
 - Science and Technology
 - o Organized programming contests, gaming contests, tech workshops.

References

- Abubakar Choudhury
 - CPA Canada
 - o CFO AT LSA Education
 - o https://www.linkedin.com/in/abubakarchoudhury/
 - o +1 (514) 715-7274 (CA)
- Shahed Islam
 - o Co-Founder And CEO of SJ Innovation LLC
 - https://www.linkedin.com/in/sjinnovation/
 - o +1(718)781-4451(US)